<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Pascal 👋</title>
    <link>https://padasch.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hi, I&#39;m Pascal 👋</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://padasch.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Song of Carbon And Nitrogen: Part 1 - The Setting</title>
      <link>https://padasch.netlify.app/posts/2023-01-12_ascan_part1_setting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://padasch.netlify.app/posts/2023-01-12_ascan_part1_setting/</guid>
      <description>Part 1 - The Setting Have you ever looked at a forest and wondered about where all this wood comes from? Like all plants, trees have the magnificent capability to draw gaseous carbon dioxide from the air and turn it into hard touchable wood. But trees do not only need carbon to grow. Like humans, they need other nutrients to build their leaves, stems, and roots. A major nutrient to do so is nitrogen - another element well hidden from our eyes that actually makes up about 80% of our earth’s atmosphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beer Afterwards is (probably) More Important Than the Talk Before it</title>
      <link>https://padasch.netlify.app/posts/2022-07-26_the-beer-after-the-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://padasch.netlify.app/posts/2022-07-26_the-beer-after-the-conference/</guid>
      <description>Too Long, Didn’t Read  Scientific conferences are for meeting people - use that opportunity! Asking questions as a fresh PhD is intimidating but not a reason to hold back. Try to get into a private conversation if you do not feel comfortable asking after a talk. Have a goal in mind of what you want to get out of the conference - are there any people you want to talk to about a specific question?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Open Science and Good Data Management is Important</title>
      <link>https://padasch.netlify.app/posts/research_data_management_2022-07-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://padasch.netlify.app/posts/research_data_management_2022-07-01/</guid>
      <description>Too Long, Didn’t Read:  The world of data is chaotic and a lot of research is not reproducible due to non-standardized, improper ways of handling and publishing data. Be part of the solution and stick to a data management plan early on in your research to force you to think about gathering, handling, publishing, licensing, and storing data that you, your peers, and the broad public can use for decades to come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://padasch.netlify.app/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://padasch.netlify.app/about/</guid>
      <description>Who am I? My passion lies in applying the possibilities of rapid technological advances to improve our understanding of how ecosystems function and to improve our environmental decision-making.
 Education  2022 - now: PhD in Climate Science, University of Bern 2019 - 2022: MSc Environmental Sciences, ETH Zürich - with distinction 2016 - 2017: Studies in Philosophy, Univeristy of Zurich 2015 - 2019: BSc Environmental Sciences, ETH Zürich   Curriculum Vitae  This browser does not support PDFs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academia</title>
      <link>https://padasch.netlify.app/academia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://padasch.netlify.app/academia/</guid>
      <description>Publications  In Review: Schneider, P.D., Gessler, A., Stocker, B.D., 2023. Photosynthesis acclimates to warming through predictable changes in photosynthetic capacities, stomatal sensitivity and enzyme kinetics (other). display. https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-egu23-12108
 Fang, X., Muntwyler, A., Schneider, P., Christl, I., Wang, P., Zhao, F.-J., &amp;amp; Kretzschmar, R. (2022). Exploring Key Soil Parameters Relevant to Arsenic and Cadmium Accumulation in Rice Grain in Southern China. Soil Systems, 6(2), 36. https://doi.org/10.3390/soilsystems6020036
 Schneider, P.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
